<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Golang on Crazcalm</title>
    <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/tags/golang/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Golang on Crazcalm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:44:46 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/tags/golang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Programming Oversight...</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/programming_oversights/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2017 13:44:46 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/programming_oversights/</guid>
      <description>The Problem I have a horrible memory. If I meet 10 people at a party, I might remember 2 of their names. Recently, I started teaching English in China, and I now have 300+ students. In the spirit of facing my memory problem head on, wrote a programmatic solution.
Flash Cards App I built my own flashcard app! You can find the project on Github at https://github.com/crazcalm/flash-cards. In summary, I used Golang to build a terminal application that reads a csv file and turns that content into flashcards.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang: Using Google&#39;s x packages in China</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/go_x_packages_in_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 15:33:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/go_x_packages_in_china/</guid>
      <description>The Issue While in China, I do not have access to Google services, websites, or platforms. In terms of being a Golang user, this is annoying because a ton of Golang projects and packages use the x packages, which are a set of Golang packages that were built by Google. These packages are hosted on a Google server, so I end up seeing a lot of this:
$ go get -u github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Micro: My New Editor?</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/learning_micro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2016 19:03:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/learning_micro/</guid>
      <description>Why Learn Micro? I have no good reason as to why someone should learn micro over some other text editor. With that being said, here are some reasons as to why I want to learn how to use this editor.
 It is written in Go.
 I am trying to learn Go, so a text editor written in Go appeals to me.  Writing Go code in it is easy!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>