<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>China on Crazcalm</title>
    <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/tags/china/</link>
    <description>Recent content in China on Crazcalm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 18:39:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/tags/china/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Captcha FAIL!</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/captcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 18:39:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/captcha/</guid>
      <description>I am not a ROBOT!!! I am currently in China and I already do not have access to a lot of sites (Thanks China!). Now Google is blocking the few sites that I do have access to with their Captcha interface! I have no access to Google, so I have no way of completing the Captcha! Given that implementing a captcha is standard practice in tech, I just lost access to the rest of the Western World&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Golang: Using Google&#39;s x packages in China</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/go_x_packages_in_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2017 15:33:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/go_x_packages_in_china/</guid>
      <description>The Issue While in China, I do not have access to Google services, websites, or platforms. In terms of being a Golang user, this is annoying because a ton of Golang projects and packages use the x packages, which are a set of Golang packages that were built by Google. These packages are hosted on a Google server, so I end up seeing a lot of this:
$ go get -u github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Move to China: My Technical Difficulties</title>
      <link>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/move_to_china/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2017 23:29:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://crazcalm.github.io/blog/post/move_to_china/</guid>
      <description>What I was prepared for: When planning a move to China, we all think of the obvious things we will lose the ability to use; All Google products, Facebook, Whats App, Twitter, Instagram, etc. I have known people who have purchased VPNs so that they could continue using those services, but I am not one of those people.
What I did not expect: Distance issues The biggest issue I have ran into has been the physical distance between China and the Western world.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>